Neufeld, Maurice Documents and Clipping Files 5777
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Maurice Neufeld Documents and Clipping Files
1946-1987
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Neufeld, Maurice F.
5777
11 cubic feet
11 linear ft.
Records (documents).
5702255
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 01, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 02, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Professor Maurice Frank Neufeld (October 27, 1910 -April 10, 2003) was an American academic, author, union organizer and Army officer. In 1945, he was one of the two founding faculty members of the School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University, appointed by its founding dean, Irving Ives.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3001: Jean T. McKelvey Papers /3007: Maurice Neufeld Papers /3007 AV: Maurice Neufeld "Grass Roots Founders and Grass Root Prodders: The Sources of Venture and Renewal for Democratic Education" Speech Audio-Visual Materials /3012: Alice Cook Papers /4104 OHT: ILR School 40th Anniversary Interviews /4131m: Maurice Neufeld Additional Papers /4135 OHT: ILR School Founding Faculty Oral History Project /4165 OHT: Jean T. McKelvey Interview with Ronald Schatz /4180: Jean T. McKelvey Additional Papers /4191 AV: ILR School Audio-Visual Department Video Cassette Collection /4202: Jean T. McKelvey Additional Files /4202 MB: Jean T. McKelvey Memorabilia /4202 P: Jean T. McKelvey Photographs /4229: Maurice Neufeld Additional Files /4229 AV: Maurice Neufeld "The Future of the American Labor Movement" Audio-Visual Materials /4230: Maurice Neufeld Additional Files /4289 P: ILR School Alumni Affairs and Development Photographs /4297: ILR School Biography Files 5216: Theresa Wolfson Papers 5937: Walton E. Burdick Papers 5982: Winifred Wanderse Research Notes on Frances Perkins and Incomplete Manuscript 5982 AV: Winifred Wandersee Collection of Frances Perkins Audio-Visual Materials 6038 P: Photographs Archival Collection 6118 AV: Kheel Center AV Collection
Collective bargaining.; Employment forecasting.; Industrial relations.; Incentives in industry.; Commerce.; Revenue.; Administration.; Neufeld, Maurice F.
5702255
- Administration-Collective Bargaining. (Box 1)
  - Administration- Public 33.01, 1941-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administration General- 33 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administration General 33 (Folder 3 0f 3), 1951-1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aged 68 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agriculture 01, 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arts and Architecture 58, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Arts and Architecture 58.02, 1973-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arts and Architecture- ancient 58.01 (Folder 1 0f 1), 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arts and Architecture- American 2 58.02 (Folder 2 0f 2), 1973-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bibliographies and Indexes 02 (Folder 1 of 2), 1963-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bibliographies and Indexes 02 (Folder 2 of 2), 1948-1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bibliographies and Indexes- Greenwood 02.01, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Civil Liberties and Civil Rights 03 (Folder 1 of 3), 1963-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Civil Liberties and Civil Rights 03 (Folder 2 of 3), 1943-1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Civil Liberties/ Civil Rights 03 (Folder 3 of 3), 1951-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Collective Bargaining 04 (Folder 1 0f 5), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Collective Bargaining 04 (Folder 2 of 5), 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Collective Bargaining 04 (Folder 5 of 5), 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Community Services-Education. (Box 2)
  - Community Services and Community Dispute Settlement 05, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Conciliation, Mediation, Arbitration, Fact finding 06 (Folder 1 of 3), 1945-1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Conciliation, Mediation, Arbitration, Fact finding (Folder 2 of 3), 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Conciliation, Mediation, Arbitration, Fact Finding 06 (Folder 3 of 3), 1963-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, Professional Groups 07, 1947-1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Conflict Management 11, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Consumer Interest, 1970-1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cooperatives- Consumer and Producer 59, 1939-1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Defense Mobilization and Demobilization 56, 1951-1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Discrimination 08 (Folder 1 of 2), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Discrimination 08 (Folder 2 of 2), 1960-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Economics, Economic Theory, Economic Development 49 (Folder 1 of 3), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Economics, Economic Theory, Economic Development (Folder 2 of 3), 1961 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Economics, Economic Theory, Economic Development 49 (Folder 3 0f 3), 1964-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Education 09, 1940-1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Education-Employment and Unemployment. (Box 3)
  - Education 09 (Folder 2 of 9), 1948-1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Education 09 (Folder 3 of 9), 1948-1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Education 09 (Folder 4 of 9), 1960-1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Education 09 (Folder 5 of 9), 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 09- Education (Folder 6 of 9), 1948-1963 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 09- Education (Folder 7 of 9), 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Education 09 (Folder 8 of 9), 1972-1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Education 09 (Folder 9 of 9), 1972-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Education- Academic Freedom 09.01, 1950-1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Continuing Education 09.05, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 09.04 Education- Industrial Relations- Institutes and Schools, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - International Affairs 09.02, 1966-1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 09.03 Education- Vocational, Technical, Professional, Retraining, 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Employment and Unemployment 10 (Folder 1 of 10), 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Employment and Unemployment 10 (Folder 2 of 10), 1946-1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Finance and Taxation-History (American Biography). (Box 4)
  - Employment and Unemployment 10 (Folder 3), 1961-1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Finance and Taxation12, 1946-1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Foundations 61, 1955-1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Government General 13, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Government Federal 13.01 (Folder 1 of 2), 1946-1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Government- Federal 13.01 (Folder 2 of 2), 1970-1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Government- Federal- CIA, 1966-1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Government- Military (Folder 1 of 2), 1945-1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Scope and Contents
    Some documents in Italian
  - Government- Military 13.03 (Folder 2 of 2), 1945-1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Some documents in Italian- same documents as Gov.- Mil. Folder 1 of 2
  - Government- State and Local 13.02 (Folder 1 of 2), 1935-1941 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Government- State and Local 13.02 (Folder 2 of 2), 1944-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 39.01- Health and Medical Care, 1963-1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - History- General 14, 1962-1970 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - History- Africa 14.11, 1971-1975 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - History- American- Bibliography and Generae 14.01, 1948-1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - History- American- Bibliography Generae14.01, 1948-1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - History- American- Biography, Autobiography, Memoirs 14.011, 1970-1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- History (American Civil War)- American Social History. (Box 5)
  - History- American Civil War 14.012, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - History- American Colonial (American Revolution-1789) 14.013, 1942-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - History- American Constitutional and Legal 14.002, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - History- American- Diplomatic 14.003, 1979-1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - History- American Economic 14.014, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - History- American- Frontiers and Regional 14.015, 1955-1975 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - History- American Intellectual, 1946-1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - History- American Intellectual 14.016 (Folder 2 of 3), 1964-1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 14.016 History American Intellectual, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - History- American 1789- Civil War, 1963-1982 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - History- American 1865-1929 14.018, 1932-1973 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - History- American 1920-1965 14.019 (Folder 1 of 3), 1923-1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - History- American 1920-1965 (Folder 2 of 3), 1963-1984 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - History- American 1920-1965 (Folder 3 of 3), 1937-1967 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - History- American 1965-present 14.020 (Folder 1 of 3), 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - The Nixon Years 14.020 (Folder 2 of 3), 1975 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 14.020 Watergate (Folder 3 of 3), 1974 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - History- American Social 14.001 (Folder 1 of 3), 1938-1959 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - History-American Social 14.001 (Folder 2 of 3), 1966-1986 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 14.001 (Folder 3 of 3), 1972-1983 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- History (American Negro)-Housing. (Box 6)
  - History- American Social- Negro 14.0011 (Folder 1 of 3), 1938-1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - History- American Social- Negro 14.0011 (Folder 2 of 3), 1932-1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Clippings from Newspapers
  - American History- Social- Negro (Folder 3 of 3) 14.0011, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Indian History 14.0012, 1957-1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 14.0013-American Social- Spanish Speaking, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Ancient History- 14.03, 1944-1955 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 14.05 Asian History, 1949-1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - History- Canadian 14.13, 1964-1982 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - History- Economic 14.02, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    One document in another language
  - History- English 14.09, 1933-1965 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - History- European Medieval 14.071, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - History- European Modern 14.072 (Folder 1 of 2), 1919-1966 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - History- European Modern 14.072 (Folder 2 of 2), 1968-1974 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - History- European Renaissance 14.073, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - History- European 16th century 14.074, 1933-1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 14.09 Folder 2, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - History- Intellectual 14.12, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - History- Historiography 14.09 Folder 1, 1970-1984 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - History- Latin America 14.10, 1961-1986 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - History- Nationalism 14.15, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - History- Science and Technology 14.16, 1966-1970 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - History- Social 14.14, 1966-1984 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - History- World 14.06, 1951-1976 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Housing 15, 1946-1970 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Incentive Plans-Labor Relations Legislation. (Box 7)
  - Incentive Plans, To 16, 1950-1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Income and Wealth 17 (Folder 1 of 2), 1947-1973 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Income and Wealth 17 (Folder 2 of 2), 1956-1970 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Inflation 19, 1952-1977 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Judicial Review and Labor Relations 22, 1963-1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 21-21. 54 Labor, General and Labor, Women, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 21.27-21.279- Labor Other Countries- International Federations and Organizations, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 50 Labor Courts, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Labor Depts. Municipal 63.01, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Labor Depts. National 63.02, 1969-1978 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 63.03 Labor Depts.- State, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Labor- Management Cooperation 23, 1963-1977 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Labor- Management Cooperation 23 (Folder 2 of 2), 1947-1979 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Labor Market and Workforce 55, 1970-1974 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 24 Labor Relations, 1957-1982 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 24.01 Labor Relations Boards (Folder 1 of 2), 1937 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Labor Relations Boards- Municipal 24.011, 1954-1966 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - National Labor Relations Boards 24.012 (Folder 1 of 2), 1944-1959 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - National Labor Relations Boards 24.012 (Folder 2 of 2), 1946-1950 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Labor Relations Board- State 24.014, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Labor Relations Legislation 54 Folder 1, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Labor Relations Legislation- Literature. (Box 8)
  - Labor Relations and Legislation 54 (Folder 2 of 4), 1942-1948 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Labor Relations Legislation 54 (Folder 3 of 4), 1954-1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Labor Legislation 54 (Folder 4 of 4), 1953-1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Labor Theory- Ideology 25 (Folder 1 of 2), 1944-1953 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 25 Labor Theory and Ideology (Folder 2 of 2), 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Literature 26, 1963-1968 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Literature- African 26.06, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - American Literature 26.01 (Folder 1 of 2), 1900-1966 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - American Literature 26.01 (Folder 2 of 2), 1968-1986 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Literature- American Negro 26.011, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Literature- Ancient 26.05, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Literature- Asian 26.07, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Literature- English 26.02, 1965-1984 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 26.03 European Literature, 1965-1983 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Literature- Latin American 26.08, 1977-1981 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Literature- Social Protest 26.04 (Folder 1), 1945-1965 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Literature- Social Protest 26.04 (Folder 2), 1968-1971 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Maps-Productivity. (Box 9)
  - 27 Maps (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Military and Naval Affairs 28, 1946-1967 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Personnel Management and Human Relations in Industry 29 (Folder 1 of 2), 1958-1965 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Personnel Management and Human Relations in Industry 29 (Folder 2 of 2), 1977 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Philosophy 60, 1933-1981 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Planning, Conservations and Urban Development- 30 (Folder 1 of 3), 1938-1940 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 30 (Folder 2 of 3), 1947-1962 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 30 (Folder 3 of 3) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 30- (Folder 3 of 3), 1943-1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 52- Political Theory, 1950-1967 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - 52.01 Politics (Folder 1 of 2), 1968-1986 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - 52.01 (Folder 2 of 2), 1954-1987 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Population and Demography 30.01, 1963-1982 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - 31 Prices and Price Control, 1947-1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - 31 Productivity (Folder 1 of 3), 1966 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - 32 (Folder 2 of 2), 1958-1963 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Productivity 32 (Folder 3 of 3), 1962-1978 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Profits-Trade and Commerce. (Box 10)
  - 32.01 Profits, 1949-1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Public Opinions, Surveys, Polls 53, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Public Relations 34, 1947-1967 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Public Relations- Ind. 34.01 (Folder 1 of 2), 1946-1948 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Public Relations- Unions 34.02 (Folder 2 of 2), 1946-1966 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 35 Quotations, 1965-1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - 36 Race Relations, 1962-1976 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Religion 62, 1964-1984 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Research and Research Agencies 65, 1967-1971 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Safety- Industrial 37, 1952-1977 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 38 Science, 1949-1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - 39 Social Security and Welfare (Folder 1 of 3), 1949-1958 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - 39 (Folder 2 of 3), 1949-1954 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - 39 (Folder 3 of 3), 1966-1983 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - 40, 1978-1983 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - 57- Sociology, Psychology, Anthropology, Linguistics, 1963-1973 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - 51 Statistical Data, 1976-1982 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Strikes and Strike Legislation 41 (Folder 1 of 2), 1941-1963 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - 41 (Folder 2 of 2), 1946 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Trade and Commerce 42, 1962-1968 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- UN and Foreign Affairs-LUOM Leadership. (Box 11)
  - UN and Foreign Affairs 43 (Folder 1 of 3), 1946-1948 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - UN and Foreign Affairs 43 (Folder 2 of 3), 1966-1971 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 43 (Folder 3 of 3), 1965-1973 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 44 Veterans Affairs, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 45 Wages and Hours (Folder 1 of 3), 1945-1946 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 45 Wages and Hours (Folder 2 of 3), 1947-1962 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 45 (Folder 3 of 30, 1960-1982 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - 46 Wage and Hour Legislation, 1946-1972 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - 67 Women, 1972-1983 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 47 World War II and Subsequent Wars (Folder 1 of 2), 1942-1973 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - 47 (Folder 2 of 2), 1977-1986 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - 64 Youth Movements, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - 48.17 LUOM Leadership, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 13)